# Michael Kelly

2192 Garfield Rd Auburn, MI 48611 mike@plusonedevelopments.com http://resume.plusonedevelopments.com (989) 714-3269



## SUMMARY

A self-motivated tech enthusiast with experience in both hardware and software. I am currently pursuing my bachelor's degree in Computer Science, with a focus on project management and software development.

I have many years of experience in the IT industry where I have enjoyed the challenge of maintaining my education in a fast paced field. The time I have spent as an IT consultant has given me valuable experience working with small and medium businesses on solving important problems within restrictive budgets. Because of these experiences, I have developed a talent for creative problem solving that would be an asset for any modern company.

#### SUMMARY OF SKILLS

- Eight years of extensive Computer and Equipment repair experience
- Five years IT/networking experience
- Four years of programming experience, specializing in php and mySQL driven web applications.

#### Languages:

- Git Repository <a href="https://github.com/plusonedev">https://github.com/plusonedev</a>
- Proficient in: PHP, JavaScript, Python
- Familiar with: C, Visual Basic
- Databases: MySQL, mongo DB, becoming familiar with neo4j (graph database)
- · Platforms: Windows server, Linux server (specializing in Debian and its derivatives)

## **EXPERIENCE**

IT Manager 6/30/2010 - Current

Bishop Energy Services

- Management of a Windows and Linux based network, Active Directory based authentication, and MySQL database management. All systems run virtualized on a VMware ESXi server.
- Designed work flow for a residential and commercial customer program that managed customer enrollments with two major utility companies. Developed customer management software in PHP and python for every day use and sustained 99.99% uptime.
- Developed embedded systems controller for a bio-fuel furnace based on an Atmel Mega processor with firmware written in C.

## **Information Technology Consultant**

6/28/2008 - Current

Plus One Developments

- Workflow and online strategy advising
- Software development
- Web & mobile development

## **EDUCATION**

## Delta Community College University Center, MI 2012-2016

 3.98 GPA – Phi Theta Kappa - Currently enrolled and pursuing an associate's degree in Computer Science – Programming (will be transferring associate's to Saginaw Valley State University to pursue a bachelor's degree)

Vassar High School Vassar, MI 1997-2001

- General Education Diploma
- · Computer repair & web design studied at Tuscola Technology Center

### **REFERENCES**

Mark Livernois – Current Customer (989) 941-0018 Services Supplied: Email Hosting / Webdesign

James Chilton – Current Customer (989) 430-3699

Services supplied: Social Media Strategy Consulting